你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
欢迎回来。
And welcome back.
因此，在上一个视频中，您学习了如何使用几个命令打开文件并读取其内容
So in the last video you learned how to open files and read their contents by using several command
行命令，例如cat命令将打开一个文件，并允许我们读取其内容。
line commands So for example the cat command will open up a file and allow us to read its content.
所以如果我们用来表示1.60，我们可以看到它包含单词Hello。
So if we use for a 1.60 we can see that it contains the word Hello.
当我们像这样打开文件时，所有内容都会同时显示出来。
And when we open files like this what happens is everything is shown all at once.
因此，无论文件有多长，它都会被直接吐到我们的终端中，这是一种善意的做法
So no matter how long the file is it will all be spat out right into our terminal and that can be kind
痛苦的感觉。
of pain.
例如，如果我们试图打开一个非常长的文件，比如我在上一篇文章中展示的文件
So for example if we try to open up a really long file such as the file that I showed you in the last
与您系统中的打印机和设备有关的视频。
video which has something to do with printers and stuff on your system.
所以如果我输入的话警察就会浏览网站。
So if I typed that in so cops browsed dot com.
好的。
OK.
我试着打印。
And I try to print.
你可以看到我们刚刚拍摄了一大堆信息。
You can see that we've just shot a whole bunch of information.
如果我们想要阅读它，我们必须在命令行中像这样上下滚动。
And if we want to read it we've got to scroll up and down like this right in our command line.
就像这样有点痛苦，这不是一种很好的方式。
It's a bit of a pain right like this not really a nice way.
您希望能够处理长文件。
You want to be able to deal with the long files.
因此，为了帮助实现这一点，Linux上有一些称为分页程序的程序，它们允许您翻页
So to help with this there are programs on Linux called pager programs that allow you to page through
较大的输出，使其更易于阅读。
large output to make it easier to read.
我们将在这段视频中介绍的是最后一个命令。
And the one that we'll be covering in this video is called the last command.
因此，如果我们只是做，而不是猫，如果我们做得更少，然后给它我们想要读的父亲，你可以看到
So if we just do instead of cat if we do less and then give it the father we want to read you can see
现在的情况是，我们首先在文件的顶部进行排序，只需使用我们的键盘
now what's happening is we are we sorted first of all at the top of the file and by just using our keyboard
向上和向下的键或箭头键，我们可以滚动浏览此内容并阅读，还可以上上下下骑车阅读
keys or arrow keys up and down we can scroll through this content and read it and bicycling up and down
这比我们只在命令行中使用它容易得多，如果我按Q，您可以在底部看到它
a lot easier than if we had it just on the command line and if I press Q You can see it on the bottom
嘿，我们有这两个冒号，如果我键入q，它就会关闭。
Hey we got these two colons if I type q it closes.
然后他们又重新开机了。
And they were back on.
来吧，我的，没有乱七八糟的，我们必须滚动通过。
Come on my with no mess that we have to scroll through.
所以这是一个很好的方法。
So that's a nice way of doing it.
实际上，您可以通过管道连接到最后一个命令，所以我可以使用它，而不是直接打开它
And actually you can pipe to the last command so instead of opening it directly about I could use that
打开文件，然后通过管道进入最后一个命令，它会给我们相同的结果。
to open the file and then pipe into the last command and it will give us the same result.
现在，这种通过管道连接到最后一个命令的能力非常有用，因为它不一定要
Now this ability to pipe to the last command is incredibly useful because it doesn't just have to be
您正在处理的文件。
files that you are that you are dealing with.
例如，如果我说OK，让我们进入我们的主目录，找到所有的文本文件。
For example if I said OK let's come into our into our home directory and let's find all the text files.
好的，我们要按名字找到所有以点TXI结尾的东西。
Ok so we're going to find by name everything that ends in Dot TXI.
好的。
OK.
我们看到我们在这里得到了一大堆信息，这可能需要相当长的时间。
And we see that we get a whole bunch of information here and this could be quite long.
可能会有很多东西。
It could it could be quite a lot of stuff.
但是我们要做的是，我们要做的不是，实际上攻击的结束是
But what we're going to do is we're going to instead of that actually the end of just attacks is to
试着找出一切都好，它打印了一大堆东西，我们必须滚动浏览。
try and find everything OK it's printed out a whole bunch of stuff that we've got to scroll through.
取而代之的是，我们可以用管道把它换成更少的。
Instead of that we can just pipe it into less.
现在我们可以逐行滚动。
And now we can scroll through line by line.
最后这条注释在使用命令行时非常有用，因为它使您
So this last comment is a really useful one when working with the command line because it saves you
因为你的屏幕上到处都是乱七八糟的东西。
from having a lot of mess filling up your screen.
好的。
OK.
给它铺设管道真的很有用。
And piping to it is is really really really useful.
我们能解救的案子和所有乱七八糟的东西现在都没了。
The cases that we can to rescue and all the mess has gone now.
有时，您不想要整个小时或整个文件，而只想对其中的一部分进行操作
Sometimes you don't want the whole hour or the whole file and you only want to operate on a piece of
它。
it.
好的，那么也许您想从文件中提取一小部分，并将其通过您的管道进行传递
OK so perhaps you want to take a little piece from a file and pass it through your pipeline instead
整个文件都在你的屏幕上，你只想在上车前浏览一小段
of having the whole file on your screen and you just want to peek at a little piece before getting on
你的工作。
with your work.
因此，出于此目的，我们可以使用head命令允许您执行的head和ail命令
So for this purpose we can use the head and the tail commands that the head command will allow you to
看到从文件顶部或头部开始的一小段文件，Tail命令将
see a little piece of the file starting at the top or the head of the file and the tail command will
反其道而行之。
do the opposite.
它希望看到文件的一小部分从文件的底部或尾部开始。
It would like to see a little piece of the file starting at the bottom or at the tail of the file.
好的。
OK.
例如，让我们再次将以下文件连接在一起，我将转到我们的桌面
So for example let's concatenate together the following files again I'm going to get to our desktop
清空屏幕，我要把文件，哎呀，剪辑放在一起，一个文件到一个文件
and clear the screen and I'm going to cut together files oops clips being kept together files one to
五。
five.
好的。
OK.
那需要两个人。
That takes two.
我们看到我们排出了五排。
And we see that we get five rows out.
好的。
OK.
现在，如果我把它输入head命令，我们就会得到相同的输出。
Now if I just pipe this into the head command we just get the same output.
那为什么呢。
So why is that.
这是因为head命令在默认情况下是文件的前10行
Well that's because the head command were by default so we the first 10 lines of a file and since there
只有5行，我们将看到所有内容，但是我们可以通过指定需要的行数来编辑此行为
are only five we'll see it all but we can edit this behavior by specifying how many lines that we want
去看看。
to see.
所以如果我按下路障来得到我们想要的，我就可以发表仇恨言论
So if I just press the barricades to get what we want I can give the the hate speech that had come out
并指定我们想要查看的行数，这样我们将只看到前两行
of the option and specify how many rows we want to see so we're just going to see the first two lines
你们会看到我们开始了，我们只看到Hello在那里，输出的前两行。
and you'll see that we go we just see Hello in there the first two lines of the output.
现在，head命令在管道中再次非常有用。
Now the head command is very useful in pipeline's again.
假设我们正在执行find命令，我们回到主目录并运行find命令
Let's say we were doing the find command and we're back in our home directory and we run the find command
我们得到了一大堆输出，假设您只想要这些选项中的前五个选项
we get a whole bunch of output and let's say you just wanted the first five of these options you can
只需通过管道将其发送给head命令，给它一个选项，然后说，嘿，我只需要五行代码。
just pipe it to the head command give it an option and say Hey I just want five lines.
让我按Enter键。
Let me press enter.
你看，我们开始了，我们得到了前五个结果，然后你可以把这些结果放下来
And you see there we go we get the first five results and then you can take those and pipe them down
不管你想要什么原因都会顺着管道走下去。
down the then the pipeline for whatever reason you wanted.
所以也许我想，你知道，然后Paso进入任务指挥部，颠倒他们所处的顺序
So maybe I wanted to you know then Paso's into the task command and reverse the order that they're in
或者不管它是什么。
or whatever it might be.
好的。
OK.
所以这是HEAD命令的一个非常有用的应用程序，它的工作原理与Tail命令相同，但是
So that's a really useful application of the head command that works the same for the tail command but
Tail命令将从底部而不是从顶部向您显示。
the tail command will show you from the bottom rather than from the top.
但我想告诉你的是，实际上你不需要直接用管子砸脑袋，来吧，你可以做手术
But I want to show you that actually you don't need to just pipe to the head come on you can operate
直接放在文件上。
directly on files.
所以我们有一个很长的落差，不是吗，我们有，它是在C杯，杯子，浏览网站。
So we had that really long fall didn't we we had it was slush at C cups cups browsed dot com.
你看，我们有很长很长的档案。
And you see we got this really really long file.
现在，如果我们可以通过管道将其传递给字数统计命令，并给它
Now if we can actually see how long that is by piping that to the word count command and giving it the
选项，就像你在课程前面看到的，你可以看到我们有673行，相当多
option like you've seen a bit earlier in the course you can see we've got 673 lines that's quite a few
台词。
lines.
但如果我们只想要前20条线路和一套管道呢？
But what if we just want the first 20 lines with a set of piping it.
我们没必要这么做。
We don't have to do that.
我们能做的就是说Head得到前20名的选择权，然后把它给外国人
What we can do is we can just say head get the option of the first 20 and then give it the foreigners
直接操作，我们将只得到前20条线路，我们可以确认我们确实有
operate directly on and we will get just the first 20 lines and we can confirm that we do indeed have
20行，按此处的向上箭头键，然后使用选项向右输送到字数统计命令
20 lines by pressing the up arrow key here and piping right to the word count command with the option
来计算线条的数量，我们会看到这一点。
to count the amount of lines and we'll see that up.
我们现在只有20行输出。
We do now only have 20 lines of output.
所以这很完美。
So that's perfect.
现在，除了从底部开始之外，Tail命令的工作方式与HEAD命令基本相同
Now the tail command works basically the same way as the head command except it starts from the bottom
一份文件。
of a file.
如果我们再做一次选角，我们就会回到桌面上，我们的卡托文件4：59停靠在这里。
So if we do our casting again we get back to the desktop and we Cateau file 4:59 docked here.
我们会看到这一点的，但我们还是会向你们打招呼的，你们这些漂亮的人。
And we'll see that yet we get hello you beautiful people.
如果我们把它告诉尾部指挥官，说我们只想要最下面的两条线，那么我们就
And if we pipe it into the tail commander and say we just want the bottom two lines then we'll just
找漂亮的人来。
get beautiful people.
所以最下面的两条线。
So the bottom two lines.
好的。
OK.
如果我们再一次对非常长的文件进行操作，所以不是用现金而不是
And if we again we're operating on the really really long file so instead of having cash instead of
有了头，让我们有尾，去掉这个单词的尾数。
having head let's have tail get rid of this word count at the end.
现在，如果我们按Enter键，您可以看到我们只得到最下面的20行，我们可以再次通过管道
Now if we if we press ENTER you can see that we just get the bottom 20 lines and we can again pipe that
进入字数统计，可以看到，是的，我们确实有20行。
into word count and see that yes we do indeed have 20 lines.
因此Head和Tail分别剪切文件的顶部或底部，以精确控制
So head and tail to cut either the top of a file or the bottom of a file respectively to control exactly
你想要什么。
what you want.
你可以把这些组合在一起，形成过滤的特定线条。
And you can use these together to kind of filter out specific lines.
好的。
OK.
所以让我们说我们做了，让我们回到头的例子，让我们假设我们去掉了前20行。
So let's say we did let's go back to our head example and let's say that we cut out the first 20 lines.
好的。
OK.
这是那个又大又长的文件的前20行。
These are the first 20 lines of that big long file.
然后，如果我把它输入Tail命令，而盖茨说，好的，只给我从底部算起一行。
And then if I pipe that into the tail command and Gates said OK give me just one line from the bottom.
好的，那么这里的这个空格将是文件的第20行。
OK then this blank here is going to be the 20th line of the file.
也许这不是那么令人兴奋，比方说，如果我得到3个好的。
Maybe it's not that exciting let's say if I get say three OK.
这将给我提供文件的第18、19和20行。
That's going to give me lines 18 19 and 20 of the file.
您可以用这种方式使用命令来删除特定的行。
And you can use the commands in this way to cut out specific lines.
好的，这就是一个非常有用的组合。
OK so that's that's quite a useful combination right there.
但这些东西真正发挥作用的地方是在你建造管道的时候。
But really where these things come into coming to their real use is when you are building your pipeline.
因此，我一直使用并依赖的示例是find命令，因为它为我们提供了大量输出
So the example I've been using and leaning on is the find command because it gives us a lot of output
但是你知道，如果你只想要一组特定的线条，比如说我想要最后三条线条，我可以
but you know if you wanted to just get a specific set of lines say I wanted the last three lines I could
只需将这些输入到Tail命令中，然后说OK，只需给我最后三行，然后继续
just pipe those into the tail command and just say OK just give me the last three lines and then continue
要将其记录下来，甚至将其导出，让我们比方说，将桌面上的文本导出，然后您
to pipe that down or even export it lets say into export the text on our on our desktop and then you
我可以保存并保留您想要的行，而不是必须有一大堆输出
can save up and keep just the lines that you want rather than having to have a whole bunch of output
你不需要的东西。
that you don't need.
好的，就像过滤一样。
OK so it's like a filter.
Head和土库曼人最好被视为过滤器，让你的管道能让你得到你想要的东西
The head and Turkomans are best seen as filters that allow your pipelines to get you just what you want
一起工作。
to work with.
所以我们在过去的几个视频中有相当多的东西，对吧。
So we've got quite a lot of stuff in the past few videos right.
但幸运的是，这些都不是特别复杂，但都非常有用。
But fortunately none of it is particularly complicated but it's all very useful.
简单回顾一下，您已经了解了如何使用cat命令将文件连接在一起或连接文件
So as a quick recap you've seen how to join files together or concatenate files using the cat command
这是一个很棒的工具，不仅可以联合起来，还可以让您获取错误的内容
which is a great tool for not only joining forces but also allowing you to take a false content and
将其直接放入标准输出，以便在您的管道中使用。
putting it right into standard output so that it can be used in your pipelines.
您还了解了如何垂直反转文件。
You've also seen how you can reverse files vertically.
因此，使用TAC命令，您还了解了如何使用以下命令在各行之间水平反转文件
So using the TAC command and you've also seen how to reverse files horizontally across their lines using
使用ref命令并同时使用这两个命令是将您的文件弄乱的一种非常好的方法。
the ref command and using both of those together is a real good way to jumble up your files.
现在，您想要读取的一些文件非常长，只能用Capcom查看它们的内容
Now some files that you want to read are very very long and just viewing their contents with the Capcom
举个例子，它有点乱七八糟的，给你提供了很多你必须滚动浏览的东西。
and for example is a bit of a mess and it gives you a lot of stuff you've got to scroll through.
因此，您了解了如何使用less命令对大量输出或来自的大文件进行分页
So you saw how to use the less command to page through massive amounts of output or large files from
命令行，不需要创建不必要的文件，只需查看命令的输出和管道
the command line without needing to make unnecessary files just to view the output and piping from commands
到最后一条命令是保持终端整洁和提高工作流程效率的好方法
to the last command is a great way to keep your terminal tidy and make your workflow more effective
使处理大量数据变得更容易。
and just make dealing with large amounts of data a lot easier to handle.
最后，您了解了如何使用Head和Tail命令从文件中剪切出您想要的内容。
And finally you saw how to use the head and tail commands to cut out just what you want from a file.
你知道，如果你愿意的话，那就直接把它传到你的管道里。
And you know if you would like then pass it straight on down your pipeline.
因此，这些都是非常有用的工具，在处理文件内容时会经常派上用场。
So these are really really useful tools that will come in handy quite often when working with file content.
现在，您不仅知道如何整体操作文件，也知道如何复制整个文件、移动整个文件、删除整个文件
So now you not only know how to manipulate files as a whole so copy a whole file move a whole file delete
整个文件，但现在您知道如何对其内容进行更多操作。
the whole file but now you know how to operate a bit more on their contents.
但是，您可以对文件内容做的事情太多了，只需简单地查看或粘贴它们即可
But there's so much more that you can do with file contents and simply just looking at them or sticking
他们在一起。
them together.
在下一个视频中，您将了解如何按字母顺序对命令文件内容进行排序
So in the next video you're going to learn how you can sort a command files contents either alphabetically
或者用数字表示，并且能够对内容进行排序是非常有用的。
or numerically and being able to sort content's is super useful.
它使查找您想要的东西变得更容易，并且与HEAD等命令完美地配合使用
It makes finding what you're looking for easier and works perfectly alongside commands such as the head
和我们在这段视频中看到的尾部命令来进行非常强大的组合，忘记了
and tail commands that we've seen in this video to make really powerful combinations forgetting just
你想从一个文件里得到什么。
what you want out of a file.
因此，这将是史诗般的文件分类是一项非常非常有用的能力。
So this is going to be epic sorting files is just a really really useful ability.
好了，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for all that goodness I'll see you in the next video.